usmle-forums.com 2012-03-13

# Privacy Policy of USMLE Forums Website

At USMLE forums, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.usmle-forums.com and how it is used. 

**Log Files**

Like many other websites, USMLE Forums makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies**

USMLE Forums does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitors sends via their browsers.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

**Google Ads**

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on USMLE Forums website.
  * Google's use of cookies enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to USMLE Forums website and other sites on the Internet.
  * Google ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on USMLE Forums website send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used to measure the effectiveness of the advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.
  * USMLE Forums website has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by Google Ads.
  * You should consult the respective privacy policies of Google ads for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Users may opt out of the use of the cookies by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>.
  * USMLE Forums privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

**Website Statistics**

As with most of the websites in the Internet we collect visitors information as they visit the various pages of the USMLE Forums website. We do that via the use of cookies and tracking codes and scripts to collect industry standard information such as geographic locations, referral origins, time on site, which links are clicked, and other information. This will help us improve the site lay out and design to provide the most suitable user experience. However, we don't use such information to track personal data nor that we share it with other third parties. The information gained is completely anonymous to analyze trends and statistics. USMLE Forums uses [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/index.html) and [Quantcast](http://www.quantcast.com/) to collect such kind of information.

**Users Information**

USMLE Forums users have complete control over which information they'd like to share with other users and visitors to the USMLE Forums website. Our users email database is stored in a secure server and is only used to relay communications when users opt in and we don't share it with any third parties outside USMLE Forums. Users email address is not revealed to other users and visitors in the user profile even when the respective user opted to receive emails from other users and visitors. Please refer to our public profile FAQ page for more information.

**Promotional Emails**

If checked YES to "USMLE News & Promotional Emails" upon registration you will be receiving these emails. However, please note that even if the email is promoting third party products or services, it was not sent from these advertisers. Our members emails are strictly stored in our database and is not shared with advertisers. You can always opt out of these emails by going to your User control panel and check the No answer.

**Monthly Contest Winners**

Currently we provide free USMLE Consult subscription to our Monthly Contest winners. USMLE Consult requires the following information before they can provide us with the activation codes; Full Name, Country of Residence, and a Valid Email Address. Please note that this information is intended solely for the activation of your USMLE Consult subscription.

**If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free toContact us.**
